<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/"
  version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>bdharva</title>
    <link>www.bdharva.com</link>
    <description>RSS feed for bdharva</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Y Combinator Interview</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/blog/yc-interview</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I went out on a limb and shot off an application to Y Combinator&amp;#8217;s winter session. I&amp;#8217;ve been putting a lot of time and effort into developing BrainGuard over the last few months, and it finally felt like time to start reaching out for funding and mentorship that could help to more rapidly accelerate development. With many initial milestones passed and a decent functional prototype in hand, my next steps would be in domains outside of my core area of expertise, and I figured I could use all of the help I could get. Fortunately, some combination of the concepts behind BrainGuard and the (too many) words of my application resonated enough with the partners at YC for them to invite me to an interview at their office in Mountain View.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MA State Highpoint</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/blog/MA-highpoint</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got out and knocked another highpoint off the list this weekend. In recent months I&amp;#8217;ve been so focused on developing prototypes for my start-up (and doing freelance design work to cover food and rent) that I&amp;#8217;ve barely been outside, let alone had a chance to head into the mountains for a weekend. So, with a few late nights of staying up to knock out extra work, I managed to create a comfy enough time buffer to bag a highpoint (and have time left over to follow the Red Sox playoff run as any Boston devotee must).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphic Design</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/completed/graphic-design</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite my more rational and technical propensities, I&amp;#8217;ve always also had a fairly artistic side. From a young age, I filled all of my school notes with sketches, doodles, and other drawings unrelated to what I should&amp;#8217;ve been taking notes on. In particular, logos always fascinated me, and many of my doodles featured logos of my favorite sports teams or those of teams I dreamt up. When I got to college, I started to learn how to &amp;#8220;digitally sketch&amp;#8221; vector graphics in a free program called Inkscape. I soon took over the duties of making party fliers and rush shirts for my fraternity, and was often responsible for any graphic design and layout associated with group projects for my classes. My architecture coursework gave me the opportunity to begin to fully develop as a designer, with access to more sophisticated tools and professional critique from my instructors. To this day, Inkscape continues to be my favorite program to work with, and I&amp;#8217;ve managed to leverage my proficiency with the program into regular paid design work through my small design company, &lt;a href='http://www.birddoginnovations.com'&gt;Birddog&lt;/a&gt;. I also continue to do design work for my fraternity (though I&amp;#8217;m hoping to pass the torch soon, through seminars to share what I&amp;#8217;ve learned with current undergrads) and I&amp;#8217;m always happy to do free work for friends and family in need of design help. Below are samples of some of my recent work, both personal and professional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clean Slate Anxiety</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/blog/clean-slate-anxiety</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve finally done something I&amp;#8217;ve been meaning to for a while and completely overhauled my personal website. It&amp;#8217;s something I&amp;#8217;d fiddled around with for years, constantly changing the structure and design and jumping between content management solutions. As evidenced by the constant changes, something was never quite right about any given iteration. There was always something missing, and, as I progressively became more well-versed in web design, I finally resolved to rebuild from scratch. About the time I completed this process, a friend introduced me to Jekyll. So much for being finished with the constant changes&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrainGuard</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/current/brainguard</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had a handful of concussions over the course of my life, including, most recently, a rather severe on while at MIT, I understand firsthand the very real dangers associated with traumatic head impacts in amateur athletics. I&amp;#8217;m looking to develop hardware and software solutions as part of a multi-pronged approach to monitoring and detecting such dangerous impacts, and to promote more effective and informed responses by parents, coaches, and players in the wake of a significant event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Birddog Innovations</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/current/birddog</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.birddoginnovations.com'&gt;Birddog&lt;/a&gt; is a bit of an accidental venture. When my partner and I first started working together on design and photography, it was out of frustration with our current work situation. We were part of the same management training program, where we found ourselves bored out of our minds and completely unchallenged, despite our constant attempts to make more of the experience. At some point we realized that we both had quite a few overlapping interests, including web design and photography. Soon we were working together every night after work, sharing tricks and tips for everything from responsive layout to search engine optimization, and digging into the intricacies of Adobe Lightroom&amp;#8217;s post-processing capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bottle Openers</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/completed/bottle-openers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s no secret - I love beer. I love it so much that I went to work for the world&amp;#8217;s largest brewer after graduation, and was lucky enough to learn just about all there is to know about beer from some of the world&amp;#8217;s best brewmasters. During my time working there, my training class completed a project called &amp;#8220;Build-a-Brand&amp;#8221;. Split into two competing teams, we worked to design completely new beers from scratch, brew them, design packaging and branding for them, and develop marketing and production plans for their launch. The project culminated with their unveiling to upper management at our training program&amp;#8217;s capstone event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2013-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood-Framed Inverted Roof</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/completed/shed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Needing more space in our garage for actually parking vehicles, my family determined that it was necessary to build a secondary storage space to house lawn mowers, bicycles, and all of the other clutter from our garage. I was lucky enough to have parents that were trusting (and supportive) enough to allow me to design the structure and oversee its construction. The entire process was incredibly rewarding, as I got to go through design iterations, permiting, surveying, budgeting, and all of the various aspects of actual construction. And the completion of the project would not have been possible without all of the helping hands that friends and family lent throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2012-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epic American Roadtrip</title>
      <link>www.bdharva.com/blog/roadtrip</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy to say that, following the most amazing two weeks of my life, I am safely back in Boston (in one piece). In my fraternity it&amp;#8217;s somewhat of a tradition to take a pledge class roadtrip between the end of classes and commencement (MIT has a roughly 2.5 week gap). Most years an RV or a large passenger van is rented for a week-long trek between the houses of the graduating brothers living on the east coast (ie. reasonable driving ditance from Boston). My class landed on a loftier goal &amp;#8211; we resolved to visit every single pledge brother&amp;#8217;s house on the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <dc:date>2012-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <dc:date>2013-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</dc:date>
  </channel>
</rss>